Guide to the General Collection Manuscript Music Miscellany
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Ponchielli, Amilcare, 1834-1886
  - Music
    - Unidentified
      - Fragments from a mass, n.d.; 3 score fragments. (Box Folder 325)
        Purchased from David Schulson Autographs on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
      - Sketches, undated; [8] p. of ms. music; 31 cm., in binding, 32 cm. (Box Volume 52)
        Sketches, holograph, for an unidentified aria with text beginning "Turbina o vento del deserto."
        Purchased from Lisa Cox on the Edith and Richard French Fund, 2003.
- Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963
  - Correspondence
    - Auric, Nora, [1941] Jan 1; 1 item (2 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 326)
      ALS, discussing the German occupation of France, and referring to Georges Auric, Nadia Boulanger, and his incidental music for Léocadia by Jean Anouilh.
      Former group number: 63 POULENC, FRANCIS
      Purchased from Bernard Quaritch Ltd. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Haas, Monique, n.y. Jul 19; 1 item (2 p.); 10 x 14 cm. (Box Folder 327)
      AL, possibly incomplete, discussing Haas's performance of a work by Poulenc and referring to his Dialogues des Carmélites.
    - Unidentified, [1927 Feb]; 1 item (3 p.); 20 cm. (Box Folder 328)
      ALS, Brussels, to "Cher ami," concerning a concert of music by Poulenc and Igor Stravinsky.
  - Music
    - Le bestiaire. La sauterelle. Vocal score
      Song cycle for voice, violin, flute, clarinet bassoon, and string quartet, with text by Giullaume Apollinaire. Composed 1919.
      - Quotation from Le bestiaire, 1919; [1] p. of ms. music; 27 cm. (Box Folder 392)
        Quotation from La sauterelle, from Poulenc's song cycle Le bestiaire, vocal score, holograph, with brief explanatory notes, signed.
        Dated at end, 1919 printemps.
        Purchased from Librairie Musicale Ancienne on the Philip and Margaret Neufeld Fund of the Yale Library Associates, 2003.
- Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924
  - Correspondence
    - Bettolacci, Antonio, [1911]; 1 item (4 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 329)
      ALS, with envelope, Rome, regarding an invitation to Bettolacci, "signora Orlando," and Eugenio Niccolini.
      Former group number: 64 PUCCINI, GIACOMO
    - Bettolacci, Antonio, 1914 Sep 13; 1 item (postcard); 9 x 14 cm. (Box Folder 330)
      ANS, Milan, to Bettolacci, Torre del Lago, arranging a meeting. Accompanied by five postcards and four photographs showing sites in Torre del Lago related to Puccini, a postcard photograph of Puccini, an obituary and a clipping about him, and typescript notes concerning these materials, in French, by an unidentified writer.
      In Italian; notes are in French.
    - Franceschini, Albina, 1911 Apr 15; 1 item (2 p.); 25 cm. (Box Folder 331)
      ALS, Milan, to Franceschini, Pescia, consisting of a poem, with first line "Quest' è l'imagine".
    - Lori, Amedeo, 1909 Jan 5; 1 item (2 p.); 25 cm. (Box Folder 332)
      ALS, Torre del Lago, to Lori, Florence, concerning letters from Lori and referring to Puccini's work in Torre del Lago.
    - Schiff, Violet, 1914 Jan 10; 1 item (2 p.); 25 cm. (Box Folder 333)
      ALS, Torre del Lago, to Schiff, Rome, concerning a trip to London.
      In Italian. Accompanied by a computer-printed English translation.
    - Seligman, Sibyl, [1919] Sep 1; 1 item (2 p.); 19 x 31 cm. (Box Folder 343)
      ALS, Torre del Lago, to Seligman, London, discussing cigarettes and referring to Alfred Kalisch and Violet Schiff.
    - Seligman, Sybil, [1906 Nov 2 and 26]; 3 items. (Box Folder 334)
      Three brief ALS, Paris, praising Seligman, referring to his difficulty with sleeping, and arranging a meeting.
    - Seligman, Sybil, [1906 Nov]; 1 item (4 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 335)
      ALS, Paris, concerning Marguerite Carré in the role of Madama Butterfly, and referring to Enrico Caruso and Francesco Paolo Tosti.
    - Seligman, Sybil, 1907 [Jul 7]; 1 item (2 p.); 25 cm. (Box Folder 337)
      ALS, Torre del Lago, to Seligman, London, about La fanciulla del West, discussing an Italian translation of the play by David Belasco.
    - Seligman, Sybil, 1910 Oct 8; 1 item (6 p.); 25 x 25 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 29)
      ALS, Torre del Lago, to Seligman, London, sending an advance copy of La fanciulla del West, discussing possible subjects for operas, including Spanish plays by Joaquín and Serafín Alvarez Quintero and Angel Guimerá, and referring to Eugen d'Albert and L'oiseau bleu by Maurice Maeterlinck.
    - Seligman, Sybil, [1910 Jun 6]; 1 item (4 p.); 17 cm. (Box Folder 340)
      ALS, Paris, about rehearsals for Manon Lescaut in Paris, discussing Lucrezia Bori, Enrico Caruso, and Arturo Toscanini, and referring to his work on La fanciulla del West.
    - Seligman, Sybil, 1919 Apr 6; 1 item (2 p.); 25 x 31 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 30)
      ALS, Torre del Lago, to Seligman, London, about the engagement of a conductor and singers for Il trittico at Covent Garden, discussing Henry Vincent Higgins, Thomas Beecham, Arturo Toscanini, Margaret Sheridan, and Marie-Louise Edvina.
    - Seligman, Sybil, [1907 Jun 15]; 1 item (4 p.); 22 cm. (Box Folder 336)
      ALS, Paris, discussing upcoming productions of his operas in Brussels and Vienna, including Madama Butterfly; discussing performances of Fortunio by André Messager and Ariane et Barbe-bleue by Paul Dukas; and referring to Sir Paolo Tosti, Violet Schiff, "Farcone," and "Savage".
    - Seligman, Sybil, 1911 Jan 28; 1 item (2 p. ); 25 cm. (Box Folder 341)
      ALS, Torre del Lago, to Seligman, London, concerning his search for a libretto for a new opera.
    - Seligman, Sybil, 1911 Apr 14; 1 item (2 p.); 25 cm. (Box Folder 342)
      ALS, Milan, to Seligman, Naples, regarding his arrival in Milan and plans for departure for London.
    - Seligman, Sybil, 1919 Oct 13; 1 item (2 p.); 12 x 17 cm. (Box Folder 344)
      ALS concerning Seligman's health.
    - Seligman, Sybil, 1907 Dec 3; 1 item (2 p.); 25 cm. (Box Folder 338)
      ALS, Bolgheri, to Seligman, London, concerning La fanciulla del West and Carlo Zangarini.
    - Seligman, Sybil, 1908 Aug 25; 1 item (2 p.); 25 cm. (Box Folder 339)
      ALS, Torre del Lago, to Seligman, Venice, concerning La fanciulla del West.
    - Zuccoli, Guido, [1924 Sep 11]; 1 item (1 p.); 27 cm. (Box Folder 345)
      ALS to Zuccoli, at Puccini's publisher Ricordi, concerning his work on Turandot.
  - Music
    - Inno a Diana
      Song, with words by Carlo Abeniacar.
      Published 1899.
      - "Inno a Diana / musica di Giacomo Puccini; parole di Carlo Abeniacar", 1897 Dec 12; 1 ms. score (6 p.); 33 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 31)
        Song, copyist's manuscript, corrected in holograph and signed by Puccini. Appended is an ALS from Puccini to Abeniacar, [1897 Dec 13], presenting the score and discussing Puccini's interest in hunting.
        Purchased from Lisa Cox (Sotheby's, 1998 May 21, lot 308), on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund
- Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943
  - Music
    - Etudes-tableaux, op. 33. Selections; arr.
      Originally for solo piano; arranged by Respighi for orchestra, 1930.
      Former group number: 65 RACHMANINOFF, SERGEI
      - "5 etudes tableaux / S. Rachmaninoff; orchestration de Ottorino Respighi", 1930; 1 ms. score (100 p.); 41 cm. (Box Volume 25)
        Score, in Respighi's holograph, with corrections, dated at Rome, 1930 Sep 30.
        Purchased from Bernard Quaritch on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
- Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937
  - Music
    - Menuet antique
      For solo piano.
      Composed 1895; first performed 1898, by Ricardo Vinès.
      - "Menuet antique / Maurice Ravel", 1898 January 5; 8 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 84)
        Engraved proof (Paris: Enoch & Cie., 1898), with holograph corrections.
        Stamp: "première epreuve," Enoch & Cie., 1898 January 5.
        Stamp: J. B. Baudon, Paris, "gravure de musique."
        Plate number: E. & C. 3616 (Enoch & Cie.).
        Annotated in an unidentified hand: "à Louis Diemer."
        Ownership stamp of Ricardo Vinès.
        Purchased from J & J Lubrano on the Edith and Richard French Fund, 2002.
- Reszke, Edouard De, 1853-1917
  - Correspondence
    - Lowenfeld, M., Mr. and Mrs., 1911; 1 item (visiting card); 6 x 9 cm. (Box Folder 346)
      AN written on a printed visiting card, with envelope.
      Former group number: 66 RESZKE, EDOUARD DE
      Gift, 1950.
- Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868
  - Music
    - Bianca e Falliero
      Opera, with libretto by Felice Romani, after A.-V. Arnault's Blanche et Montcassin.
      First performed 1819; vocal score published 1828.
      - Bianca e Falliero. Atto 2, [circa 1819]; 1 ms. score ([circa 350] p.); 23 x 31 cm. (Box Volume 53)
        Act 2, score, contemporary copyist's manuscript in several unidentified hands, with a few revisions.
        Binding: contemporary half calf with marbled boards; front board missing and spine detached.
        Purchased from Bernard Quaritch, Ltd., (Sotheby's sale, 2002 December 6, lot 147) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2003.
- Roussel, Albert, 1869-1937
  - Correspondence
    - Emmanuel, Maurice, 1935 October 18; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 417)
      Autograph letter, signed, about a missed meeting, and referring to Emmanuel's Symphony no. 2, op. 25.
    - Prunières, Henry, 1929 March 25; 1 item (4 p.). (Box Folder 416)
      Autograph letter, signed, about performance of Roussel's Psalm 80, op. 37, for tenor, chorus, and orchestra. With an enclosed copy of the psalm text in English.
      Letter is in French.
      Purchased from David Schulson Autographs on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2003.
    - Woollett, Henry, [1905?] February [15?]; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 412)
      Autograph letter, signed, with envelope, thanking Woollett for expressing appreciation of Roussel's music. Accompanied by an autograph music quotation, signed, from Roussel's Le festin de l'araignée, 1921 April 5, with an unidentified autograph music quotation, signed, by Isidore Philipp, 1921, on verso.
      Purchased from Bernard Quaritch on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
    - Unidentified, 1910 April 28; 1 item (4 p.). (Box Folder 411)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "Monsieur," presenting an enclosed music quotation, signed, from Roussel's Suite for piano, op. 14, F sharp minor, Sicilienne; discussing the relationship between French and English contemporary music; and referring to an article by the recipient.
    - Unidentified, no year July 8; 1 item (4 p.). (Box Folder 415)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "mon cher ami," about finances of the Société Nationale de Musique, and referring to Gustave Bret.
  - Other Papers
    - Descriptions of his music, undated; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 414)
      Autograph manuscript, briefly describing composition, premiere, and movements of his Trio for piano and strings, op. 2, and Sonata for violin and piano, no. 2, op. 28.
    - Lecture on the evolution of modern music, [1936]; 1 item (18 p.). (Box Folder 413)
      Autograph manuscript lecture, given in Mulhouse, 1936, at the request of Philippe Strubin, about the development of music from the mid 19th through early 20th centuries.
    - Notes about his music and music of other composers, [ca. 1935]; 1 item ([6] p.); 14 x 21 cm. (Box Folder 347)
      Notes, holograph, referring to his Aeneas and Le testament de la tante Caroline, and to music of Claude Debussy, Igor Stravinsky, Alban Berg, Darius Milhaud, and Paul Hindemith.
      Pages numbered 1-5.
      Former group number: 67 ROUSSEL, ALBERT
    - Speech given at the Conservatoire de musique de Bordeaux, [ca. 1935]; 1 item (4 p.); 27 cm. (Box Folder 348)
      Speech, holograph, signed, concerning music education and the future of music.
    - Translation of a concert review, [1935?]; 1 item (1 p.). (Box Folder 418)
      Autograph manuscript French translation of a review of a performance of music by Roussel, including his Joueurs de flûte, op. 27, and Quartet for strings, op. 45, originally appearing in Politiken (Copenhagen), 1935 November 24.
      Accompanied by a newspaper clipping of the original review.
      In French and Danish.
- Roze, Marie Hippolyte Ponsin, 1846-1926
  - Other Papers
    - Signature, n.d.; 1 item (1 p.); 7 x 10 cm. (Box Folder 349)
      Signature, with "U. S. Hotel" written underneath.
      Accompanied by notes of a former owner.
      Former group number: 68 ROZE, MARIE HIPPOLYTE PONSIN
      Gift of Harold Lamport, M.D., and H. L. Friedman, 1961.
- Saint-Amans, Louis, 1749-1820
  - Music
    - Sonatas, violin, piano
      - "Sonate pour le piano avec accompagnement de violon / composée et dédiée à Mademoiselle Roullet par L. J. St. Amans", 1805 December 13; 1 ms. score ([17] p.); 33 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 57)
        Score, manuscript, with dedication signed and dated at Brest, 1805 22 frimaire (December 13).
        Pages numbered 67-76 (rectos) and 1-13 (versos).
        Purchased from Piasa on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
- Saint-Cricq, Caroline de
  - Music
    - Unidentified
      - Vocal music collection, [circa 1825-1830]; 1 v. of music ([circa 250] p.); 32 cm. (Box Volume 54)
        Bound collection of printed and manuscript music, circa 1820s, apparently owned by Caroline de Saint-Cricq. Contents are mostly printed scores for sacred vocal music, by Luigi Cherubini, Louis-Emmanuel Jadin, J. B. Drocourt, and others. Also present are French national songs and piano music, printed and manuscript, some relating to the French Revolution, by Etienne Nicolas Méhul, Adolphe Nourrit, and others. Some music includes manuscript revisions and other annotations in an unidentified hand.
        Caroline de Saint-Cricq (born circa 1810) was a daughter of Pierre-Laurent-Barthélemy, comte de Saint-Cricq, who served as French minister of commerce, 1828-1829. In 1827 she studied music with Franz Liszt, with whom she had a brief love affair. In 1830 she married Bertrand d'Artigaux.
- Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921
  - Correspondence
    - Astier, Clara, 1907 Nov 23; 1 item (4 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 350)
      ALS discussing a tour of Madrid and Barcelona.
      Former group number: 69 SAINT-SAENS, CAMILLE
    - Fischer, Adolphe, 1883 Nov [5?]; 1 item (3 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 351)
      ALS, with envelope, Paris, to cellist Adolphe Fischer, Paris, seeking assistance in engaging musicians for a performance of his La lyre et la harpe.
    - Joncières, Victorin, 1913 Apr 2; 1 item (3 p.); 20 cm. (Box Folder 352)
      ALS, referring to a performance of choral music by Saint-Saëns.
    - Renaud, Armand, 1892 Jan 7; 1 item (3 p.); 20 cm. (Box Folder 353)
      ALS, Algiers, to Renaud, librettist of Saint-Saen's cantata Nuit persane, concerning their collaboration.
      Purchased from Moirandat Company AG (Saggiori, Geneva, lot 29) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Unidentified, 1905 Jul 22; 1 item (3 p.); 17 cm. (Box Folder 358)
      Brief ALS, Paris, to "Mon cher ami," announcing his arrival from Switzerland and plans to return there.
      Purchased from Clive Farahar & Sophis Dupre on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item (3 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 361)
      ALS to "Monsieur," declining an invitation to perform in Arras.
    - Unidentified, 1900 Sep 28; 1 item (4 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 357)
      ALS, Saint-Germain-en-Laye, to "Madame,"concerning the death of her husband.
    - Unidentified, 1878 Aug 9; 1 item (3 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 354)
      ALS, Paris, to "Monsieur," requesting cancellation of a performance because of his health.
    - Unidentified, 1917 Dec 26; 1 item (2 p.); 28 cm. (Box Folder 359)
      ALS to "mon cher ami," concerning his reactions to medieval costumes and sets in Richard Wagner's Die Meistersinger von Nuernberg and Parsifal.
      Purchased on the Coe American Studies Fund, 1958.
    - Unidentified, 1918 Aug 12; 1 item (1 p.); 27 cm. (Box Folder 360)
      ALS to "Mon cher poete" concerning an upcoming visit.
      Purchased from Pierre Berès (Drouot, 1997 Nov 6-7, no. 233) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Unidentified, 1896 Feb 11; 1 item (2 p.); 25 cm. (Box Folder 356)
      ALS, Luxor, Egypt, to "Mon cher ami", referring to his opera Frédégonde and discussing his experiences in Egypt.
    - Unidentified, 1888-1997; 5 items. (Box Folder 355)
      ALS to "mon cher ami," 1888 Dec 22, and ALS to "tres cher et vénéré confrère," 1897 Jul 24, expressing gratitude; ALS to "Chère Madame," 1889 Feb 12, discussing the death of his mother; and two ALS to "mon cher ami," 1893 Apr 5, and 1893 Jul 30, referring to Ernest Guiraud, Charles Gounod, Jules Massenet, and Ambroise Thomas.
  - Music
    - La fontaine
      Song for voice and harp.
      - "La fontaine: pour soprano avec accompagnement de harpe / C. Saint-Saëns; poèsie de Ronsard", 1903; 1 ms. score (5 p.); 27 x 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 85)
        Score, holograph. Signed and dated at end, 1903.
  - Other Papers
    - Cabinet photograph of CSS, n.d.; 1 photograph: b w; 16.3 x 10.6 cm. (Box Folder 362)
      Cabinet photograph of Saint-Saens, made by G. Lapierre, Photographie Nouvelle, Beziers, inscribed to Clara Astier, 1903.
  - Restricted Fragile
    - Folder 356, 1896 Feb 11; 1 item. (Box Restricted Fragile Folder 11)
- Satie, Erik, 1866-1925
  - Music
    - Scènes nouvelles
      Recitatives for Charles Gounod's opéra-comique Le médecin malgré lui, with a libretto based on Molière's play.
      Commissioned by Serge Diaghilev to replace original spoken dialogue, for a revival at the Festival Français in Monte Carlo; composed 1923, with a final vocal octet was adapted by Georges Auric from Gounod's quintet in act three; first performed January 5, 1924.
      Former group number: 70 SATIE, ERIK
      - Scènes nouvelles for Le médecin malgré lui by Charles Gounod, [1923]; 1 ms. score (94, [13], [22] p.); 36 cm. (Box Volume 26)
        Score of Satie's nine scènes nouvelles, holograph, with corrections by Satie and brief annotations written by dancer Serge Lifar and in unidentified hands. Appended are a transposition of Gounod's quintet from act three, written in holograph by Georges Auric, and a vocal score of the final octet, written in an unidentified hand, possibly that of Edouard Flament, who conducted the first performance at the Casino Theater, Monte Carlo. Laid in are a text of the quintet, typescript, and an excerpt in vocal score showing the transition to the final scene, written in holograph by Satie.
        "Médecin malgré lui: opéra comique de Gounod" -- caption title, written in an unidentified hand.
        Purchased at Sotheby's, London (2000 Dec 8, lot 209), on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
- Sauguet, Henri, 1901-1989
  - Music
    - Jeux de l'amour et du hasard
      For two pianos.
      Composed 1932.
      - Proofs for Jeux de l'amour et du hasard, 1932, 1958; 2 scores; 35 cm. and smaller. (Box Volume 55)
        Two proofs with holograph corrections: a negative photocopy of a copyist's manuscript, stamped Société des Auteurs, Compositeurs et Editeurs de Musique, 1932 July 1; and printed proof, white on blue background (Paris: Editions Max Eschig, c1958), with holograph note by Sauguet, signed, requesting a second proof, Paris, 1958 February 24.
        Stamps on Eschig proof: Pierre Grandjean, Fountainebleau, "graveur de musique," "1re epreuve," and "corrigé."
        Plate number in manuscript on Eschig proof: M. E. 6970 (Eschig).
        Purchased from Librairie Musicale Ancienne on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
- Sayn-Wittgenstein, Carolyne de, 1819-1887
  - Other Papers
    - Le vaisseau fantôme: grand opéra romantique: poème et musique de Richard Wagner, 1852 Mar 1; 1 v. ([3], 177 p.); 27 cm. + 1 fragment. (Box Volume 27)
      Holograph, with corrections and instructions for printing. Accompanied by a holograph fragment from an unidentified work of music criticism, n.d.
      Intended as part of a revision of Lohengrin et Tannhäuser de Richard Wagner, by Franz Liszt (Leipzig: F. A. Brockhaus, 1851). The revised three-part work was to be titled Trois opéras de Richard Wagner considérés de leur point de vue musical et poétique, by Franz Liszt.
      Former group number: 71 SAYN-WITTGENSTEIN, CAROLYNE DE
  - Restricted Fragile
    - Volume 27, n.d.; 1 fragment. (Box Restricted Fragile Folder 12)
- Schmitt, Florent, 1870-1958
  - Music
    - Marche du CLXIII; arr.
      Originally for band.
      Composed 1916; transcription for piano, 4 hands, published 1918.
      - "Marche du CLXIII: pour musique militaire: op. 48., no. II / Florent Schmitt", 1916 February; 1 ms. score (14 p.); 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 86)
        Transcription for piano, 4 hands, holograph score with revisions and printer's markings (Paris: Durand, 1918). Signed at end, 1916 February, Toul.
        Plate number in manuscript: 9571 (Durand).
        Purchased from J & J Lubrano on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
    - Reflets d'Allemagne; arr.
      Composed 1905.
      - "Reflets d'Allemagne: suite d'orchestre / Florent Schmitt", [circa 1906]; 1 score (65 p.); 34 cm., in binding 35 cm. (Box Volume 56)
        Arrangement for orchestra by the composer, printed score (Paris: A. Z. Mathot, c1906), with manuscript revisions and performance markings in an unidentified hand. Inscribed by Schmitt to French conductor and composer D. E. Inghelbrecht.
        Plate number: Z. 112. M. (A. Z. Mathot).
        Stamp: "D. E. Inghelbrecht 34."
        Bound by a former owner: contemporary half calf with marbled boards.
- Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915
  - Other Papers
    - Piano music. Selections
      - Piano music. Selections, 1947 April 16; 1 sound disc: analog, 78 rpm; 10 in. (Box Oversize Folder 90 (Record album storage))
        Formerly owned by Sergei Aleksandrovich Evreinow.
        Gift of Judith Metcalf, 2004.
        Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
- Scribe, Eugène, 1791-1861
  - Correspondence
    - Benoit-Champy, Madame, 1859 May 12; 1 item (1 p.) + 1 enclosure (2 p.). (Box Folder 425)
      Autograph letter, signed, presenting an enclosed autograph manuscript fragment from the libretto for Giacomo Meyerbeer's L'Africaine, act 5, last scene. The letter discusses delay in completion of the opera.
    - Unidentified, 1858 February 15; 1 item (1 p.). (Box Folder 424)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "Messieurs les Présidents et membres du tribunal," about posthumous performance of "Josepha," (Le dernier bal), an opera by Adolphe Adam with libretto by Scribe, and disputed rights to the opera involving Scribe, Adam's widow, and Émile Perrin.
- Sessions, Roger, 1896-
  - Other Papers
    - Notes on King Henry IV, Part 1 by William Shakespeare, 1915; 1 v. (ca. 160 p.); 27 cm. (Box Volume 28)
      Notes, holograph, signed, bound with printed text of the play.
      Former group number: 72 SESSIONS, ROGER
      Gift of W. N. Stokes, Jr., 1962.
- Sosen, Otto Ebel von
  - Music
    - Gummicouplet
      Former group number: 73 SOSEN, OTTO EBEL VON
      - "Gummicouplet / Text von Schwitters-Steinitz; Musik von Otto Ebel von Sosen", [19--]; 1 ms. score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 32)
        Autograph manuscript score for voice with piano accompaniment, with corrections by the composer. The text is by Kurt Schwitters and Kate Traumann Steinitz.
        Gift of Patti and Frank Kolodny.
- Soulage, Marcelle, 1894-1970
  - Music
    - Chamber music. Selections
      - [Chamber music], 1917-1934; 5 items. (Box Volume 61)